<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>The Administration Application</h1>

    <h2>What Is It?</h2>

    <p>The administration application is a web application that is
    always installed with Liquid Site. Though it, you can handle all
    the management and administration of Liquid Site, such as creating
    and designing web sites, writing web content, and managing users
    and permissions.</p>

    <h2>Where Do I Find It?</h2>

    <p>The administration application is really just a special type of
    web site, and Liquid Site allows you to move the location of it as
    you wish. By default it is available from the same URL as you used
    when installing Liquid Site, i.e. usually
    "<code>http://localhost:8080/</code>". If you use Liquid Site in a
    hosted environment, your hosting provider should give you the URL
    to the administration application.</p>

    <h2>Login &amp; Security</h2>

    <p>Obviously you don't want to allow everyone to make changes to
    your web sites, so the administration application is protected
    with a mandatory user login. Any user with a valid user name and
    password and with read access to the administration web site is
    allowed to login, but anonymous access is not accepted. In the
    figure below you can see what the login screen looks like.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The administration login screen. Only users with at
      least read access to the administration site are allowed to
      login here.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <ref url="admin-login.png">
            <object type="image"
                    url="admin-login-small.png"
                    description="The login screen" />
          </ref>
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>Normally you would restrict read access to the administration
    web site to only those users that really need to use it.
    <strong>Allowing other users to access the administration
    application is a security risk</strong> and should be avoided if
    possible. Note though, that users must have write permission to
    the objects themselves or they will not be editable. Likewise if a
    user without read access to some objects will not be able to see
    them even in the administration application.</p>

    <h2>The Home View</h2>

    <p>When logging in to the adminstration application the home view
    is shown, allowing the user to modify information about themselves
    in Liquid Site. Things that can be modified in this way includes
    the real user name, email address, and password. See the figure
    below for an example of how the home view can look.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The administration home view. This is the default view
      after a successful login and allows the user to modify his or
      her personal information.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <ref url="admin-home.png">
            <object type="image"
                    url="admin-home-small.png"
                    description="The home view" />
          </ref>
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>The home view is accessible to any user that can login to the
    administration site. The user can also see and modify all the
    information about him- or herself (except the comment field, see
    later section <ref file="users.xml">Users, Groups &amp;
    Permissions</ref>) as it is considered to be owned by the user. It
    is important to be aware of this, so that one does not rely on the
    user information to stay exactly as originally created.</p>

    <h2>The Site View</h2>

    <p>The site view opens when clicking the "Site" tab in the top
    menu. Inside the site view you can find everything related to
    creating and maintaining web sites. The view itself is split into
    an object tree to the left and a detail pane to the right. The
    tree contains the domain at the root and all objects belonging to
    it thereunder, such as sites and templates. The detail page is
    updated each time an object in the tree view is selected. See the
    figure below for an example of the initial site view.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The administration site view. This view allows managing
      everything related to the web site design, structure and
      layout.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <ref url="admin-site.png">
            <object type="image"
                    url="admin-site-small.png"
                    description="The site view" />
          </ref>
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>Modifications to the objects in the site view is made by
    clicking a corresponding button in the detail pane which either
    brings up a dialog or moves to a sequence of forms. All buttons
    are not shown at once, as they cannot all be applicable at once,
    and if a user lacks the required permissions they may not be shown
    all. Below is a list of all the available buttons (and thus
    operations) in the site view.</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <title>New</title>
        <text>Displays a form for creating a new object under the
        currently selected one. For instance, to create a new site the
        parent domain object should first be selected.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Edit</title>
        <text>Displays a form for editing the currently selected
        object. The form is mostly similar to the one used when
        creating the object.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Publish</title>
        <text>Opens a publishing dialog for the current object. By
        default the current date and time are suggested, but these may
        be modified for publishing at a future date.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Unpublish</title>
        <text>Opens an unpublishing dialog for the current object. By
        default the current date and time are suggested, but these may
        be modified for unpublishing at a future date.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Revert</title>
        <text>Opens a revert version dialog for the current object.
        This allows the deletion of the latest version of an object,
        effectively reverting to the previous one.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Delete</title>
        <text>Opens a delete dialog for the current object. This
        allows for the complete removal of all versions of an object,
        something that should normally be avoided (use unpublishing
        instead).</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Permissions</title>
        <text>Opens a permission dialog for the current object. This
        makes it possible to modify the permissions for the current
        object.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Unlock</title>
        <text>Opens an unlock dialog for the current object (only if
        it was locked). All objects are locked during editing, and if
        the "Save", "Cancel" or "Previous" buttons are not pressed
        when done, the lock will remain until manually removed through
        this dialog.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

    <p>The exact workings of each of these operations are described in
    detail in the chapter <ref file="index.xml" id="site">Designing
    Web Sites</ref> or <ref file="index.xml" id="security">Security
    &amp; Workflow</ref> for the permission and publishing
    operations.</p>

    <h2>The Content View</h2>

    <p>The content view is accessed by selecting the "Content" tab in
    the top menu in the administration application. Inside the content
    view you can find things related to creating and maintaining
    non-site specific web content, such as documents and other data.
    The content view should contain all the text and data you wish to
    publish on the web, except for the actual web site design.</p>

    <p>The content view is split in the same way as the site view and
    has the same button and operations. The difference between the
    content and site views are which objects are visible in each one.
    In the content view, only the sections, documents and related
    objects are visible. See the figure below for an example of a
    content view.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The administration content view. This view allows
      managing web content unrelated to the web site design.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <ref url="admin-content.png">
            <object type="image"
                    url="admin-content-small.png"
                    description="The content view" />
          </ref>
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>The intrincate details of creating web content are described in
    the chapter <ref file="index.xml" id="content">Creating Web
    Content</ref>.</p>

    <h2>The User View</h2>

    <p>The final view (for most users) in the administration
    application is the user view, that can be accessed by selecting
    "Users" in the top menu. The user view allows for adding,
    modifying and removing both users and groups. See the figure below
    for an example of how the user view can look.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The administration user view. This view allows
      managing the web users and groups.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <ref url="admin-users.png">
            <object type="image"
                    url="admin-users-small.png"
                    description="The user view" />
          </ref>
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>The selector "Type" at the top allows for selecting a list of
    either users or groups. An additional filter is available,
    allowing for a quick search in the list of users or groups. By
    pressing the button "Add New" at the bottom of the screen a new
    user or group can be added, depending on if a user or group list
    was being shown. Users and groups can also be edited by clicking
    their names which brings up an editing form.</p>

    <p>For the exact details on how to manage users and groups, please
    refer to the section <ref file="users.xml">Users, Groups &amp;
    Permissions</ref> in the <ref file="index.xml"
    id="security">Security &amp; Workflow</ref> chapter.</p>

  </body>
</doc>
