<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>Documents</h1>

    <h2>The Concept of a Document</h2>

    <p>Everyone knows what a document is. You hold it in your hand,
    read it, print it... But beware, in Liquid Site the concept of a
    document is a little bit different from what you're probably used
    to.</p>

    <p>A document in Liquid Site is little more than a set of document
    property values. That is, the content of a document is whatever
    values it sets for the document properties defined in the section.
    In a way, a document can be compared to a filled-out form, though
    some of the fields will probably contain longer texts.</p>

    <p>Most documents in this model will have a number of smaller
    property values, and then finally one property value containing
    the full text of the document. But the document model also lends
    itself to storing plain data or list entries, such as items in a
    todo-list, products in a web shop or similar.</p>

    <h2>Editing Documents</h2>

    <p>Documents are created and edited in the <ref
    file="admin.xml">Administration Application</ref> by choosing the
    "<strong>Add</strong>" or "<strong>Edit</strong>" buttons
    respectively. Both eventually lead to the same document editing
    form, except for minor differences. In the figure below the
    document being edited has the same properties as in figure 2 in
    the previous section.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>Editing a document. The document properties from the
      section show up as normal fields in the form, in this case the
      "Title", "Author" and "Text" fields. The editing form also
      allows attaching files to the document and changing the document
      name and parent section.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="document-edit.png"
                  description="Editing a document" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>Just as the sections, the document editing forms contain a
    <strong>Name</strong> field. It identifies the document inside the
    section and can be used to retrieve the document from web pages.
    When mapping documents to a web site with a <ref
    file="terminology.xml" id="translator">Translator</ref>, the
    document name will be used as a folder name inside the URLs. It is
    desireable to choose document names that are meaningful and convey
    information about their content, but they should also be
    relatively short and written using only the English alphabet and
    numbers. As a rule of thumb, documents should be named with all
    lower-case letters.</p>

    <p>Other fields that are always available when editing documents
    are the parent section, the attached files, and the revision
    comment. By changing the <strong>Section</strong>, a document can
    be moved around in the content tree. Doing so may break pages
    and/or URLs depending on the structure so it should be used with
    care. The <strong>Files</strong> field allows attaching files to
    the document, which further described below. Finally, a revision
    <strong>Comment</strong> must be specified when modifying a
    document, as for all other objects.</p>

    <p>When editing documents, fields for all the document properties
    from the parent section are also displayed. These fields are
    displayed with the title and description from the section, and the
    actual input control depends on the type of the document property.
    In the figure above, the controls for plain text and tagged text
    are shown.</p>

    <h2>Attaching Files &amp; Images</h2>

    <p>Documents can have any number of files or images attached. This
    makes it possible to embed links and images in the document texts
    in an easy way. It also means that these resources can be managed
    together with the document in terms of permissions, location in
    the content tree, etc.</p>

    <p>The attached files are stored separately from the document but
    the document editing form contains a simple way to attach new
    files. The figure below shows the part of the document editing
    form that allows attaching new files. Note that the file must
    first be selected (using the "Browse.." button) before the
    "<strong>Add</strong>" button can be used.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>Attaching a file to a document. The previously attached
      files are shown along with their size and MIME types. To add a
      new file, it should first be selected with the "Browse..."
      button and then added with the "Add" button.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="document-attach.png"
                  description="Attaching a file to a document" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>Attached files are seen in the content view under the document,
    as if it was a folder containing the files. When using a <ref
    file="terminology.xml" id="translator">Translator</ref> the files
    are present in the virtual document folder, making it possible to
    link to them using their names directly without any path. See the
    figure below for an example of how attached files can look in the
    content tree.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>Attached files in the content tree. The files are
      attached to a document, showing the document as the parent
      object to the files.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="document-tree.png"
                  description="Attached files in the content tree" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

  </body>
</doc>
