<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>What's This All About?</h1>

    <h2>A Little Bit of History</h2>

    <p>Liquid Site was first conceptualized during the summer of 2003
    as the direct result of the authors' frustrations with a number of
    open source Content Management Systems (CMS). It was created as a
    web solution for the <ref url="http://www.sak.se">Swedish
    Committee For Afghanistan</ref> and much inspiration and many
    ideas came from <ref url="http://www.erikgustafsson.com/">Erik
    Gustafsson</ref> (then Information Coordinator at Swedish
    Committee). Although originally planned for three months in
    development, the first version of Liquid Site took a full year to
    create, although admittedly much of the work was done as a
    part-time job.</p>

    <h2>What is a CMS?</h2>

    <p>Liquid Site is a Content Management System (CMS) for web
    publishing. Using a CMS instead of static web pages or a
    custom-programmed web site has several advantages:</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <title>Separation of Content &amp; Design</title>
        <text>The web design can be modified and handled totally
        independently to the creation of web content, usually by
        different people.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Easy Content Creation</title>
        <text>It is normally much easier to create web content with a
        CMS than with other tools such as text editors or even
        specialized HTML editors.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Automatic Publishing &amp; Depublishing</title>
        <text>Publishing and depublishing of web resources based on
        date and time information is possible, allowing automatic
        removal of outdated information.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Versioning</title>
        <text>All versions of each web resource can be kept, making it
        possible to easily recover from mistakes or errors.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

    <p>When using a CMS most of these come "for free" compared to a
    custom web solution. Basing a web site on a CMS platform also
    mitigates the risk of the web site becoming a dead end, with
    outdated or unmanageable source code.</p>

    <h2>Why Use Liquid Site?</h2>

    <p>Liquid Site is a state-of-the-art CMS that attempts to be easy
    to use without sacrificing the advantages of a custom web
    solution. It is written in 100% pure Java and is primarily aimed
    at small- to medium-traffic sites with dynamic web content, but it
    should also work well in lots of other scenarios. The main
    advantages with using Liquid Site compared to other CMS are the
    following:</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <title>Dynamic Content Structure</title>
        <text>Need to store a corporate document number with some
        documents? No problem, as content is not limited to a preset
        collection of fields. Instead you define your own document
        types with any fields you need.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Fully Programmable Web Pages</title>
        <text>Need to sort documents backwards according to some
        criterion? No problem, as the web pages are fully programmable
        it is easy to modify sorting, filtering, or even to present a
        different page depending on the user.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Web Design Any Way You Want It</title>
        <text>Don't like frames? No problem, as the web site design is
        completely up to you. There are no restriction, no limits and
        no compromises. Just you and your HTML.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Search Engine-friendly URLs</title>
        <text>Like short and meaningful URLs? No problem, as you can
        have full control over them. Add your keywords to the URL and
        watch your pages become more relevant in the major search
        engines. Also, there won't be much trouble when sending URLs
        in email anymore.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Multiple Web Site Support</title>
        <text>Want to share user names across several web sites? No
        problem, as you can create as many web sites as you wish while
        still sharing the same content and user names.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

    <p>These are but a few of the reasons to use Liquid Site instead
    of some other CMS. Others include UTF-8 support, visual content
    editors and the availability of fully supported and managed
    hosting.</p>

  </body>
</doc>
