<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>Concepts &amp; Definitions</h1>

    <p>Liquid Site uses a specific terminology that is important to
    understand in order to administrate a web site. These same terms
    are also used extensively in this reference manual and in other
    documents. The list below attempts to define and describe the most
    important of these terms.</p>

    <list>
      <item id="alias" style="draft">
        <title>Alias</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="css">
        <title>CSS</title>
        <text>The <ref url="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-CSS2">Cascading
        Style Sheet (CSS)</ref> format is the most common layout and
        styling langugage used on the world wide web. The CSS format
        is text-based and readable by both humans and machines. A CSS
        file contains detailed layout and formatting instructions for
        <ref id="html">HTML</ref> documents, allowing a single style
        sheet to be used for several documents. A working knowledge of
        CSS is required in order to modify the layout of web
        pages.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="directory" style="draft">
        <title>Directory</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="group" style="draft">
        <title>Group</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="html">
        <title>HTML</title>
        <text>The <ref url="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/">HyperText
        Markup Language (HTML)</ref> is the most common document
        format used on the world wide web. The HTML format is
        text-based and readable by both humans and machines. An HTML
        document normally only contains the text and overall structure
        of a web page, using external <ref id="css">CSS</ref> style
        sheets and image files for specifying the layout. A working
        knowledge of HTML is required in order to modify the layout of
        web pages.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="page">
        <title>Page</title>
        <text>A web page contains <ref id="html">HTML</ref> code
        presenting the web content. The HTML code for each page is
        split into one or more <ref id="page_element">Page
        Elements</ref> allowing individual elements to be reused
        across different pages. Pages can inherit the page elements
        from other pages, typically <ref id="template">Template</ref>
        pages.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="page_element">
        <title>Page Element</title>
        <text>A page element is a piece of <ref id="html">HTML</ref>
        code for a part of a document. A page element may also contain
        references to other page elements, thereby creating an element
        hierarchy. Such a page element hierarchy can be inherited
        between <ref id="page">Pages</ref>, allowing overriding a
        single page element in the hierarchy. A page element is
        identified by it's name.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="request" style="draft">
        <title>Request</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="response" style="draft">
        <title>Response</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="site">
        <title>Site</title>
        <text>A web site consists of a collection of documents and
        files available from a single location on the world wide web.
        A web site is normally identified by a host name, for example
        <code>www.liquidsite.org</code>. It is also possible to share
        a single host name and separate the sites by their base
        directory. Web sites can only share information with other
        sites in the same <ref id="site_group">Site Group</ref>, but
        they can of course link to public resources on other
        sites.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="site_group">
        <title>Site Group</title>
        <text>A site group is a set of <ref id="site">Sites</ref> that
        share common resources. <ref id="user">Users</ref> and 
        <ref id="group">Groups</ref> are always shared between the
        sites in a site group. Files, templates, and pages may be
        shared by using <ref id="alias">Aliases</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="template">
        <title>Template</title>
        <text>A template is a <ref id="page">Page</ref> that is only
        used as a parent for other pages. A template page consists of
        <ref id="page_element">Page Elements</ref> with HTML code just
        as normal pages. Templates can inherit the page elements from
        other templates, creating a hierarchy of more refined
        templates.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="user" style="draft">
        <title>User</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>

      <item id="web_page">
        <title>Web Page</title>
        <text>See <ref id="page">Page</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="web_site">
        <title>Web Site</title>
        <text>See <ref id="site">Site</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="web_transaction" style="draft">
        <title>Web Transaction</title>
        <text></text>
      </item>
    </list>

  </body>
</doc>
