<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>Concepts &amp; Definitions</h1>

    <p>Liquid Site uses a specific terminology that is important to
    understand in order to administrate a web site. These same terms
    are also used extensively in this reference manual and in other
    documents. The list below attempts to define and describe the most
    important of these terms.</p>

    <list>
      <item id="acl">
        <title>Access Control List</title>
        <text>An access control list contains the <ref
        id="permission">Permissions</ref> for a resource in a <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref>. The list enumerates a set of <ref
        id="user">Users</ref> and <ref id="group">Groups</ref> and the
        assigned permission level. A user is always given the highest
        permission level possible if several entries in the this
        should match. The access control list is inherited from the
        parent resource if none is defined.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="content_view">
        <title>Content View</title>
        <text>The content view displays resources in a <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref> that are used for storing
        non-presentation data or content. Typical objects in the
        content view are <ref id="section">Sections</ref> and <ref
        id="document">Documents</ref>. Resources related to the web
        presentation of these objects are present in the <ref
        id="site_view">Site View</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="css">
        <title>CSS</title> <text>The <ref
        url="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-CSS2">Cascading Style Sheet
        (CSS)</ref> format is the most common layout and styling
        langugage used on the world wide web. The CSS format is
        text-based and readable by both humans and machines. A CSS
        file contains detailed layout and formatting instructions for
        <ref id="html">HTML</ref> documents, allowing a single style
        sheet to be used for several documents. A working knowledge of
        CSS is required in order to modify the layout and style of web
        pages.</text> </item>

      <item id="document">
        <title>Document</title>
        <text>A document consists of a set of <ref
        id="document_property">Document Property</ref> values. The
        values can have different formats and provides structured
        document data that can be retrieved and displayed on a web
        <ref id="page">Page</ref>. Each document must have a parent
        <ref id="section">Section</ref> that defines the set of
        document properties available.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="document_property">
        <title>Document Property</title>
        <text>A document property is a semantical definition for a
        field in a <ref id="document">Document</ref>. The set of
        document properties in a <ref id="section">Section</ref>
        defines the fields that the documents in that section will
        have. Each document property defines a name and a data type
        for the property, whereas the value is contained in the
        documents (similar in spirit to an XML DTD).</text>
      </item>

      <item id="domain">
        <title>Domain</title>
        <text>A domain consists of a set of related web resources,
        normally belonging to a single organization or entity. All
        resources are shared within a domain, which means that
        <ref id="user">Users</ref> and <ref id="group">Groups</ref>
        span all the <ref id="site">Sites</ref> in the domain. Note
        that a domain does not have to correlate to an Intenet domain
        name, although often that is the case. A domain may be
        registered to contain <ref id="host">Hosts</ref> from several
        Intenet domain names.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="file">
        <title>File</title>
        <text>A file consists of binary or text data for a resource on
        the world wide web. Files are primarily used for storing
        images or other binary objects, but may also be used for <ref
        id="html">HTML</ref> code. It is recommended to use <ref
        id="page">Pages</ref> for HTML content, however. Files may
        also be attached to a <ref
        id="document">Document</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="folder">
        <title>Folder</title>
        <text>A folder is used to group web resources in a <ref
        id="site">Site</ref>. If a request is made directly for the
        folder, the web resource <code>index.html</code> is
        returned.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="group">
        <title>Group</title>
        <text>A group is a set of <ref id="user">Users</ref> in a <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref>. Normally all the users in the group
        share some common important property, such as being content
        editors or similar. Groups can be used in <ref id="acl">Access
        Control Lists</ref> instead of specifying all users in the
        group. Each user can be a member one or more groups.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="host">
        <title>Host</title>
        <text>A host name identifies a computer on the Internet. The
        host name is part of the <ref id="url">URL</ref> for a web
        resource, and each <ref id="site">Site</ref> is normally
        associated with one of the host names in the <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="html">
        <title>HTML</title>
        <text>The <ref url="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/">HyperText
        Markup Language (HTML)</ref> is the most common document
        format used on the world wide web. The HTML format is
        text-based and readable by both humans and machines. An HTML
        document normally only contains the text and overall structure
        of a web page, using external <ref id="css">CSS</ref> style
        sheets and image files for specifying the layout. A working
        knowledge of HTML is required in order to modify the layout
        and style of web pages.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="lock">
        <title>Lock</title>
        <text>A lock prevents accidental overwrites to objects as a
        result of parallell editing by two or more users. Whenever an
        object is edited in any way, a lock is acquired to prevent
        other users from editing the object. Upon saving the changes
        to the object the lock is removed. If a form or a dialog is
        not closed using the proper "Save", "Previous" or "Cancel"
        buttons, a stale lock may remain and require manual
        removal.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="page">
        <title>Page</title>
        <text>A page contains the <ref id="html">HTML</ref> code for a
        page on the world wide web. The HTML code for each page is
        divided into one or more <ref id="page_element">Page
        Elements</ref>, allowing elements to be inherited or modified
        from a <ref id="template">Template</ref> page.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="page_element">
        <title>Page Element</title>
        <text>A page element is a piece of <ref id="html">HTML</ref>
        code that can be part of a <ref id="page">Page</ref> or a <ref
        id="template">Template</ref>. The page element can include
        other page elements or contain advanced processing
        instructions, as defined by the <ref
        url="http://freemarker.sf.net/">FreeMarker</ref> language. A
        page element is identified by it's name and may be inherited
        if defined in a template. </text>
      </item>

      <item id="permission">
        <title>Permission</title>
        <text>The permission level controls what operations a user or
        a group are entitled to perform on an object. There are four
        permission levels; read, write, publish, and admin. The read
        permission is required in order to read or list an object. The
        write permission is needed to modify an object. The publish
        permission is required to modify the online or offline status
        of an object. And finally the admin permission is needed for
        changing the <ref id="acl">Access Control List</ref> with
        permissions.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="section">
        <title>Section</title>
        <text>A section provides a way to group and structure <ref
        id="document">Documents</ref>. It is the equivalent to a <ref
        id="folder">Folder</ref> in the <ref id="content_view">Content
        View</ref>, but also contains the definition of the <ref
        id="document_property">Document Properties</ref> available for
        contained documents.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="site">
        <title>Site</title>
        <text>A web site consists of a collection of documents and
        files available from a single location on the world wide web.
        A web site is normally identified by a <ref
        id="host">Host</ref> name, for example
        <code>www.liquidsite.org</code>. It is also possible to
        separate sites on protocol, port number or base directory. Web
        sites can only share information with other sites in the same
        <ref id="domain">Domain</ref>, but they can of course link to
        public resources on other sites.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="site_view">
        <title>Site View</title>
        <text>The site view displays resources in a <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref> that are used for presenting content
        on the web. Typical objects in the site view are <ref
        id="site">Sites</ref>, <ref id="folder">Folders</ref> and <ref
        id="page">Pages</ref>. Data content unrelated to the web
        presentation are present in the <ref id="content_view">Content
        View</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="superuser">
        <title>Superuser</title>
        <text>A superuser is a special <ref id="user">User</ref> that
        does not belong to any <ref id="domain">Domain</ref>. Instead
        the superuser has full privileges across all domains. Some
        operations on domains can only be performed by a superuser.
        Having more than a few superusers should be avoided.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="template">
        <title>Template</title>
        <text>A template is a <ref id="page">Page</ref> that is used
        to share <ref id="page_element">Page Elements</ref> between
        pages. Templates consists of <ref id="page_element">Page
        Elements</ref> just as normal pages, but cannot be directly
        accessed on the web. Pages or other templates may inherit the
        page elements in a template, reusing or modifying individual
        page elements as needed.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="translator">
        <title>Translator</title>
        <text>A translator maps <ref id="content_view">Content
        View</ref> objects to a web <ref id="site">Site</ref>. The
        translator points to a <ref id="section">Section</ref> whose
        <ref id="document">Documents</ref> and subsections becomes
        available as virtual <ref id="folder">Folders</ref> under
        translator. In order to retrieve the contents of a document or
        a section with a translator, a <code>index.html</code> <ref
        id="page">Page</ref> must be created.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="url">
        <title>Uniform Resource Locator (URL)</title>
        <text>A uniform resource locator (URL) is used for locating
        pages and other resources on the world wide web. The URL can
        be either absolute or relative to the current resource URL.
        Absolute URLs normally start with <code>http:</code> or
        <code>https:</code>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="user">
        <title>User</title>
        <text>A user is an authenticated web site visitor. Each user
        is identified by a user name that is unique within the <ref
        id="domain">Domain</ref>. Users must log in with a password to
        authenticate themselves, otherwise the default anonymous user
        is assumed. Each user can be a member one or more <ref
        id="group">Groups</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="web_page">
        <title>Web Page</title>
        <text>See <ref id="page">Page</ref>.</text>
      </item>

      <item id="web_site">
        <title>Web Site</title>
        <text>See <ref id="site">Site</ref>.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

  </body>
</doc>
