<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>HTML &amp; Tagged Text</h1>

    <h2>Text, Formatting &amp; Markup</h2>

    <p>All document properties have a type, specifying the format of
    the property values. Currently Liquid Site supports three document
    property types; plain text, HTML and tagged text. All three are
    used for storing text and both the HTML and tagged text types
    allow storing formatting along with the text.</p>

    <p>The plain text type is used for storing unformatted text. That
    means that any linebreaks or special characters in the text will
    be converted before displaying the text on a web page (i.e. in
    HTML). Plain text is often used for simple data, such as titles,
    author names, keywords and similar.</p>

    <p>The other two text types maintain text formatting alongside the
    text. They do this by marking the specially formatted text with
    special <em>tags</em>, like "<code>&lt;b&gt;word&lt;/b&gt;</code>"
    for a word in boldface. There are several different tags
    available, and they vary between the HTML and tagged text
    formats.</p>

    <p>The HTML text editor allows editing the text with markup in a
    visal manner, showing the results rather than the tags themselves.
    This editor is built into the web browsers Internet Explorer and
    Mozilla, but does not work in other web browsers such as Opera or
    Safari. The HTML text editor is also known for behaving strangely
    from time to time, something Liquid Site has no control over. For
    these reasons, it is recommended to use tagged text instead of
    HTML in most situations.</p>

    <h2>Tagged Text</h2>

    <p>Tagged text looks somewhat similar to HTML, but has been
    simplified in several aspects. The most important difference
    compared to HTML is probably that linebreaks are conserved to the
    output, making it simple to separate paragraphs by a blank line.
    Many of the tags in the tagged text are also different from HTML,
    making them easier to remember and use.</p>

    <p>In order to create tagged text it is not necessary to remember
    all the tags available. The tagged text editor provides buttons
    and helper dialogs to make the creation of the tags much easier.
    The text to format is just selected, whereafter the appropriate
    button in the editor toolbar is pressed. See the figure below for
    an example of a text being edited in the tagged text editor.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The tagged text editor. At the top is the editor
      toolbar with buttons for nearly all types of formatting
      available in the tagged text format.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="text-tagged.png"
                  description="The tagged text editor" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>A description of the tags in the tagged text format is
    available in the online help that is opened by pressing the
    rightmost button in the editor toolbar.</p>

    <h2>HTML Text</h2>

    <p>The HTML text editor allows editing HTML either directly as it
    will be shown or in source mode. In the former mode, none of the
    HTML tags are visible and all formatting is done with the help of
    the editor toolbar. The HTML editor toolbar is mostly similar to
    the toolbar for the tagged text editor, which can be seen in the
    figure below.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The HTML text editor in direct formatting mode. All
      formatting is done by marking text and using the appropriate
      toolbar buttons.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="text-html.png"
                  description="The HTML text editor" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>As an alternative to using the toolbar buttons, the HTML editor
    source mode is available. While in this mode the HTML editor
    displays the actual HTML source code and allows direct
    manipulation of it. The HTMl source mode is activated by pressing
    the rightmost button in the toolbar, as seen in the figure
    below.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The HTML text editor in source view mode. No formatting
      toolbar buttons are available in this mode, but all HTML code
      must be entered manually.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="text-htmlsource.png"
                  description="The HTML text editor in source mode" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>The HTML editor is problematic in that it is not supported in
    all web browsers, has certains quirks in the formatting mode, and
    requires detailed knowledge of HTML to be able to control the
    formatting exactly. Also, the HTML layout mode is not able to
    properly display images or links. For these reasons the tagged
    text format is recommended over HTML for most cases.</p>

    <h2>Linking &amp; Images</h2>

    <p>Both the tagged text and HTML support hyperlinking to attached
    files, web pages in the same site or to external web sites. The
    easiest way to add a link is to select the link button in the
    editor toolbar. This will bring up a dialog similar to the one in
    the figure below.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The tagged text add link dialog. The link type field
      allows selecting between normal links, links opening in a new
      window, and mail address links. In the link dialog for the HTML
      dialog, only normal links are available.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="text-link.png"
                  description="The add link dialog" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

    <p>The link URLs entered will be processed differently depending
    on their type. The three different types of links are:</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <title>Absolute links (to other sites)</title>
        <text>Links starting with <code>http://</code>,
        <code>https://</code> or another web protocol are considered
        absolute links and will not be processed.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Root-relative links (within the same site)</title>
        <text>Links starting with <code>/</code> are treated as
        relative to the web site root, and will be converted to
        normal relative links upon display.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Relative links (to attached files)</title>
        <text>Other links are treated as relative to the document
        itself and will be converted by adding the path to the
        document when needed. To link to an attached file, simply
        enter the name of the attached file as the URL.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

    <p>Images are considered a special type of attached files. By
    attaching image files to a document, the images will become
    available for insertion in the tagged text or HTML. Pressing the
    add image button an image dialog like in the figure below will be
    shown.</p>

    <figure>
      <caption>The add image dialog. The image layout allows placing
      an image floating to the left or the right. In the HTML editor
      version of this dialog, no layout option is available.</caption>

      <content>
        <p style="illustration">
          <object type="image"
                  url="text-image.png"
                  description="The add image dialog" />
        </p>
      </content>
    </figure>

  </body>
</doc>
