<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Reference Manual</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>Users &amp; Groups</h1>

    <p>All content in Liquid Site can be protected. This makes it
    possible to only allow access or modifications from certain users
    or groups of users. The authentication and authorization scheme
    has been designed to work in as many configurations as possible,
    while keeping complexity to a minimum. Below follows a list of
    the original requirements with a brief explanation of the current
    design.</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <title>Control access for all content objects</title>
        <text>All managed content requires authorization in order to
        be accessed. Unauthenticated users may be allowed read or
        write access. This is achieved by checking every content read
        or write operation with the corresponding
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="acl">access control list</ref>.
        </text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Allow access for single users or groups of users</title>
        <text>Access to content objects can be granted either for
        single users, groups of users, or any user. The list of users
        and groups are be specified in the
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="acl">access control list</ref>
        along with the permissions for each. If a user matches several
        of the items in the access control list, the union of the
        specified permissions are used.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Separate permissions for read, write and publish</title>
        <text>In a content management system, it makes sense to
        distinguish between read, write and publish operations. Read
        is any non-modifying access, write is the operation of
        updating offline content, and publish being the operation of
        putting content online or offline. The system also has
        separate permissions for admin operations, required in order
        to modify the content
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="acl">access control list</ref>.
        </text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Allow user accounts to span related web sites</title>
        <text>Multiple related web sites are typically hosted in the
        same installation, such as "www.domain.com" and
        "forum.domain.com". All such sites can share a single set of
        users and groups, making the user experience simpler while
        allowing more efficient administration. This is achieved by
        structuring user accounts into
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="domain">domains</ref>, where
        each domain may contain several (related) web sites.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Separate user accounts for unrelated web sites</title>
        <text>Multiple unrelated web sites may be hosted in the same
        installation, allowing a hosting company to share the
        hardware and software setup between several customers. Full
        separation between the different web sites can be guaranteed
        and a user account for one site will in that case not overlap
        or conflict with a similarly named user account for another
        site. This is also achieved by using
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="domain">domains</ref>. The
        user accounts in one domains are completely separated from
        the accounts in another, allowing the same user name to refer
        to different users depending on the domain.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Allow any number of users and groups</title>
        <text>User and group names have have no inherent meaning in
        the system. They are given meaning as they are added to the
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="acl">access control lists</ref>
        of content objects. Each user may be member in any number of
        groups, and each group may also have any number of users as
        members. Users and groups must be in the same
        <ref file="terminology.xml" id="domain">domain</ref> to have
        a membership relation, though.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Allow global administrators access everywhere</title>
        <text>System maintenance and configuration, requires at least
        one global administrator user. These users do not belong to
        any <ref file="terminology.xml" id="domain">domain</ref>, and
        have full access to everything in the system. Global
        administrator accounts are also useful when hosting multiple
        domains in a single installation, such as a hosting company
        would do. It is important, however, to protect these accounts
        as much as possible.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>User authentication by password and IP address</title>
        <text>User authentication is done with passwords, while also
        allowing remote IP address checks for sensitive accounts. It
        is possible to specify a single IP address or a range or IP
        addresses, thereby limiting the access for that user to those
        addresses.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Passwords only stored encrypted or hashed</title>
        <text>All passwords are protected in the database, making it
        impossible to access them even for a system administrator.
        This is achieved by only storing an MD5 hash of the password
        in the database. This makes it impossible to retrieve the
        original password, and requires new passwords to be created
        if the user has forgotten the previous one.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <title>Protection against password attacks</title>
        <text>Some protection is provided against password dictionary
        attacks. The database is protected by adding the user name to
        the password hash, effectively making every hash value
        different. The web login is protected by delaying responses
        to invalid logins, slowing down dictionary attacks by several
        orders of magnitude.</text>
      </item>
    </list>

  </body>
</doc>
