<doc>
  <head>
    <title>Liquid Site Installation Instructions</title>
  </head>

  <body>

    <h1>Requirements</h1>

    <p>The following software is required in order to run
    Liquid Site:</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <text>Java runtime compatible with JDK 1.4</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <text>Java servlet 2.3 compatible container (for example
        Apache Tomcat 4.1 or later)</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <text>MySQL 5.0 database (or later version)</text>
      </item>
    </list>


    <h1>Installation</h1>

    <p>Liquid Site comes with a web-based installation program that
    is automatically run when a configuration file cannot be found.
    The installation program can create the database, users and
    tables required. It can also update an old version of Liquid
    Site. At the end of the installation, the full configuration is
    stored to file so that subsequent startups will skip the
    installation.</p>

    <p>A number of things still must be done before starting the
    Liquid Site installer:</p>

    <list>
      <item>
        <text>Create a data directory that is writable by the
        servlet container process (Tomcat). This directory is used
        for storing file data that for performance is not in the
        database.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <text>Make sure that the WEB-INF directory is writable for
        servlet container process (Tomcat). This directory is used
        for storing the base Liquid Site configuration file.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <text>If you are performing an update, please stop the
        servlet container, clear the temporary work directory and
        rename the old deploy directory. This will make sure that
        the new version will not interfere with the old
        installation.</text>
      </item>

      <item>
        <text>Deploy the <code>liquidsite.war</code> file to the
        servlet container. If you wish that all web requests to
        the servlet container are handled in Liquid Site (normally
        the case), you may have to rename the file to
        <code>ROOT.war</code> or find some other way to deploy
        Liquid Site as the root web application.</text>
      </item>      
    </list>

  </body>
</doc>
